ABHIJITH P

Full Stack Developer(MERN/MEAN)

📞 +91 7510720805 @ abhijithp327@gmail.com 🔗 www.linkedin.com/in/abhijith-p-64b13820a 👂 Pathanamthitta , Kerala

SUMMARY

Passionate Software Engineer with 1+ years of experience in developing web applications and backend systems. Skilled at writing clear, concise code that is easy to maintain and troubleshoot. Experienced in working with both small and large teams across multiple projects and companies. Able to work independently of remote locations or in office environments as needed by the company.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Junior Software Developer In Mern/Mean Gofreelab In Pvt. Ltd 01/2023 - Present Kochi, Kerala

- · Successfully converted whole project from Mern and Mean.
- · Assist the Development Manager or the Senior Developer, as per the company's organisational structure, with programming/coding and software design.
- Attend the company's development meetings and contribute with their programming knowledge.
- · Working on minor bug fixes.
- · Continuously improve their programming skills.
- · Gathering information from consumers about program functionality.
- · Monitoring the technical performance of internal systems.

Junior Software Developer In Mern/Mean(intern) Expertzlab Technologies Pvt . Ltd 02/2022 - 12/2022 Kochi, Kerala

- · Successfully converted whole project from Mern and Mean.
- Shadowing, mentoring, and training opportunities with experienced developers.
- Test software applications that the development team builds for efficiency and note any bugs.
- · Participate in code reviews with experienced web developers..

Junior Software Developer In Python (intern) Technovalley Sofware India Pvt. Ltd 12/2021 - 01/2022 X

- \cdot $\,$ Successfully converted whole project from Python
- Shadowing, mentoring, and training opportunities with experienced developers.
- Test software applications that the development team builds for efficiency and note any bugs.
- Participate in code reviews with experienced web developers.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science Vns Arts And Science College 2018 - 2021 Konni , Kerala

CERTIFICATES

FULL STACK DEVELOPER IN PYTHON TECHNOVALLEY Kochi, Kerala

MERN/MEAN STACK DEVELOPER EXPERTLAB Kochi, Kerala

GOFREELAB

CERIFICATE IN SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Authentication Project With React JWT Authentication

- There are Login/Logout, Signup pages using html,css,bootstrap,javascript,typescript,react,mong odb
- Project Structure for React JWT Authentication (without Redux) with LocalStorage, React Router & Axios
- Form data will be validated by front-end before being sent to back-end.
- On working with MongoDB Database

Recipe Web-app using React

- Adding food recipes and cooking easier, faster, and more convenient. In fact, such an app is a faithful assistant in the kitchen, a kind of digital scullion.
- Fontend : html,css,bootstrap,react
- Fontend : html,css,bootstrap,react
- On working with MongoDB Database

Ecommerce WebApp Using Angular

- A customer finds the website, then buys goods and services. When they've decided they're done online shopping, they move to the checkout phase.
- Front-end: Html, Css, Bootstrap, Angular
- Back-end : NojeJs, Express
- On working with MongoDB Database

Hospital management system using python

- Hopistal management website using python/Django
- Front-end:Html, Css, Bootstrap,Jquery,Javascript
- Back-end : Django/Mysql

Shopping Cart Using Redux Library

A shopping cart is essential to every e-commerce site, allowing visitors to select, reserve, and purchase a product or service, and it helps create a frictionless experience for customers.

- Frontend : Html , Bootstrap , React with Redux library
- Backend: Node js Express js
- On working with MongoDB Database

SKILLS

Tools

HTML 5 • CSS • JAVASCRIPT • BOOTSTRAP • JQUERY •

REACT • ANGULAR • NODE • EXPRESS • MONGO DB •

DJANGO • C++ • Python